<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
<meta>
<category>Blog</category>
<level>Advanced</level>'
<title>How to design Interiors by sketching</title>
<poster src="http://data.doingbydesign.com.s3.amazonaws.com/_images/udemycourses/HowToDesignInteriosBySketching.png"/>
<author>Claudia Mens</author>
<topic>Highlights and pitfalls when redoing your interior.</topic>
</meta>

<featured>
<article id="generous-gesture"/>
<article id="the-url"/>
<article id="how-to-deal-with-designers"/>
<article id="interiors"/>
</featured>

<children>
<article id="how-to-build-a-simple-kirby-site"/>
<article id="how-to-build-a-xierpa3-site"/>
<article id="the-url"/>
<article id="how-to-deal-with-designers"/>
<article id="how-to-get-into-art-school"/>
</children>

<summary>
Let’s try something impossible. Learning to design Corporate Identities through an online course is just as impossible as learning to play violin from a book. A course can describe the basics, show you hints and tips and give you good advice. And at the bottom line, it all is a matter of discipline to develop your skills.
</summary>
<chapters>
<chapter>
<lead>
Let’s try something impossible. Learning to design Corporate Identities through an online course is just as impossible as learning to play violin from a book. A course can describe the basics, show you hints and tips and give you good advice. And at the bottom line, it all is a matter of discipline to develop your skills.
</lead>
<p>But this course is a serious attempt to do both. It will describe the basics, show you basic hints and tips and give you good advice. And it will be you modest – and yet determined – coach to encourage you to go through the exercises. To develop the discipline. To improve your skills.
</p><p>So this course needs you just as much as you need the course. Although most of it is a one-way mirror conversation, I hope that the exchange of information will create an environment were you feel comfortable to work in. But not too comfortable, because acquiring skills needs just the right amount of tension and transpiration.
</p><p>
The content is this course is a compilation of our years of talking with customers and lecturing design students. At the individual level they are all different and unique – no two customers are the alike and by definition no two design project are identical – but there is also a lot they have in common. Enough to make general statements and to develop generic methods how to handle corporate identity assignments. 
<footnote>This is a footnote content.</footnote>
A little warning is in place here. In the course I will pose many bold statements, such as “Never start with the logo. Start with the identity.” and “Customers cannot tell you what they need.”, but keep in mind that I am well aware that there are always exceptions to whatever I say about design in general and corporate identities in particular. But there are several reasons to make the bold statements anyway.
</p>
<image src="http://data.petr.com.s3.amazonaws.com/_images/house/buro_stairs.png"/>
<p>
First is that in a course like this we have a limited amount of time and resources. The time you want to spend on this course is relatively short and what is more important, I don’t know the details about your design project. I can only make assumptions through the wrong side of this one-way mirror. So I have to stay positioned at a certain level of abstraction, where knowing your design project more in detail, it would have been easier to address the details of it.
</p>
<p>
Also, this is an international course. I have no idea about the country you live in, what your cultural background is and nor the corporate climate of your customer. 
</p>
<blockquote>The processes and parameters described in this course may not seem compatible. These are all parameters that otherwise would have guided the course in a more dedicated direction.</blockquote>
<p>
But the most important reason for the bold statements is that I want to challenge you <footnote>The processes and parameters described in this course may not seem compatible with your current way of working and with your environment.</footnote>
to define your own position, your own opinion about how the design process should be designed. 
</p><p>
The processes and parameters described in this course may not seem compatible with your current way of 
<footnote>As with any design project, you have to adapt the offered methods to your needs, compatible with your current way of working and with your environment.</footnote>
working and with your environment. As with any design project, you have to adapt the offered methods to your needs. You always have to do that. In any given situation. The course may give you new ideas on how to look at existing projects, to criticize your own way of working. Educate your customers about how the process should work. What the question are they should have asked. What the real definition of the design problem should have been.
</p><p>
The chapters in the course span the whole range from start to implementation and setting up the maintenance. 
</p><p>
Description of the assignment
    List of requirements
    Planning
    Cost and estimate
    Strategies of collaboration
Models
    Mood board
    Network/graph of relation
    Process of sketching
    Balance 
    Visual grammar/Bertin
    Detail management
    Design the hierarchy/Selecting+rejecting
    Iterative/recursion
    Presenting
    Direction of interpretation
    Discourse
Basic elements
    Logo
        Counter shapes
        Recursively including the other basic elements
    Name
    Grid, measurement, ratio, angle
    Typography
        Type
        Hierarchy
    Color
    Contrast, texture, structure, hierarchy
    Layout, composition, visual grammar
    Time based: morph, interpolation, focus, panning, rotating, moiré
Applications
    Stationary
    Brochures, leaflets, anual reports
    Ads, promotional materials
    3D, products, packaging, exhibitions, architecture
    Interactive media
Use cases
    Vlietland
    Dutch Republic
    Reumafonds
Testing
Implementation
Maintenance
Literature/Exercises
</p>
</chapter>
</chapters>
</document>

